# **Geoff Shumway**

Vice President, Business Expansion at Arizona Commerce Authority

### Summary

Proven executive and strategist with extensive experience in delivering measurable growth for both private and public sector companies. Elevated two companies from startup to million-dollar revenues through strategic tactics and unique client-based solutions. Demonstrated ability to create meaningful relationships at the Federal, State, County and Local levels of government.

**B2B** Contract Negotiation

**Board Management** 

**Business Development** 

Channel Management

Consultative Sales

Government Affairs

**Public Speaking** 

Public-Private Partnership Management

Site Selection Service

Statutory Incentive Rules Development

Statutory Tax and Discretionary Grant Incentive Advisement

Strategic Planning

**Territory Management** 

## Experience

### Vice President, Business Expansion at Arizona Commerce Authority

April 2013 - Present (3 years 11 months)

The Arizona Commerce Authority is the leading economic development organization for the State of Arizona. We help companies expand and grow operations by providing financial and technical assistance, workforce analysis as well as meaningful connectivity to support strategic partnerships for supply chain management and business development.

My primary focus at the ACA is facilitating the expansion of enterprise and middle market businesses in the IT, Advanced Manufacturing, Financial Services and Healthcare sectors in Arizona. Since joining the ACA as VP of Business Expansion I have facilitated more than 70 company expansions, resulting in nearly \$1B of capital investment and over 8000 jobs. I act as a key advisor for senior executives of high profile global companies, Arizona's most critical employers as well as economic development partners in the private

and public sectors seeking consultation on site selection, state tax and regulatory environment, workforce analytics and numerous statutory incentive programs.

### Director, Business Development (Contractor) at Arizona Sun Corridor Partners

August 2012 - February 2013 (7 months)

The Arizona Sun Corridor Partnership is a coalition of economic development groups representing the Flagstaff, Phoenix, Pinal County, Tucson and Yuma regions. Together, we promoted the collective business, educational and technological assets to help shape the Sun Corridor's economic future.

For companies considering expansions, we offered complimentary support with data and analysis, site selection assistance and connections to key leaders throughout the regions.

### Sales Manager at Yelp

July 2011 - May 2012 (11 months)

A website that connects people with great local businesses.

Managed a team of 12 Account Executives responsible for selling online local ad space into the SMB marketplace throughout North America.

### Director of Business Development at ID Watchdog / Lifelock

March 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 11 months)

Developed new business channel at Lifelock, targeting employers and affiliate partners to add service to benefits packages, and implemented similar approach at ID Watchdog. Created co-marketing relationships with affiliates to maximize value for shared customers with adding revenue share. Defined and implemented strategies for market penetration and sales generation, from identifying targets to building campaigns.

### Sales Manager at TW Lewis / Pulte / Del Webb

2004 - 2008 (4 years)

As onsite sales leader, met with prospective buyers and shepherded them through process, from securing mortgages and choosing options to closing escrow. Collaborated with area Realtors and hosted events to showcase homes. Managed team of seven associates and mentored college recruits.

### Education

University of Arizona

BSBA, Marketing

Arizona School Of Real Estate & Business

1999

## Volunteer Experience

### **Board Member at Global Data Center Alliance**

### November 2016 - Present

Promotion of the data center industry while educating the public about the long term and widespread economic impacts that data centers bring.

The Global Data Center Alliance hosts industry events, advocates for legislative change, and celebrates individuals, organizations, and firms that are leaders in advancing the data center industry.

# Honorary Commander, 61st Fighter Squadron, "Top Dogs" at Luke Air Force Base, 56th Fighter Wing October 2016 - Present

The honorary commander program provides the 56th FW commander and base members another way to reach out to the community. The program expands the 56th FW commander's ability to foster relationships between local civic and business leaders and base personnel.

The program allows members of the community to understand the importance of Luke, the Air Force and Department of Defense military mission. It also allows military commanders and their units to learn more about the community in which they live. Luke commanders and personnel benefit through increased association with the community and its leaders.

## Organizations

### **Arizona Association for Economic Development**

April 2013 to Present

### **Association for Corporate Growth**

July 2014 to Present

### **NAIOP**

April 2013 to Present

#### **Corenet Global**

April 2013 to Present

# **Geoff Shumway**

Vice President, Business Expansion at Arizona Commerce Authority



## 6 people have recommended Geoff

"I've worked with Geoff for several years now, initially at eBay and now at PayPal. I've always found Geoff to be professional in his conduct and amazingly timely in his communications. He excels at managing interactions with VIPs and executives. He has a clam and focused demeanor that's strategic and results driven. Call it a white glove approach to client services. If you have the chance to work with Geoff I can guarantee that you will find it to be an enjoyable experience."

— Devin Whitney, Senior Manager, State Government Relations, PayPal, was Geoff's client

"Geoff's greatest strengths are his ability to develop and maintain relationships, and navigate complex political environments. Geoff was instrumental in the passage of Arizona's Data Center Incentive legislation. His ability to build coalitions and achieve results has been a tremendous benefit to Arizona's technology industry. I would highly recommend Geoff to any organization seeking to partner with a result orientated leader with a track record of success."

— Alan Kierman, Deputy General Counsel & Assistant Secretary, IO, was with another company when working with Geoff at Arizona Commerce Authority

"It is without reservation that I recommend Geoff to organizations who are looking for a pragmatic thinker, who knows how to roll up his sleeves and simultaneously lead a project with a team oriented approach. We had the opportunity to work with each other closely, while we lobbied for a progressive data center incentive program in Arizona in 2012/2013. The leadership delivered by Geoff was instrumental in creating a coalition of data center operators to deliver a Bill which eventually passed in June 2013. Geoff's ability to listen to a client's needs; develop multiple solutions and execute with the mindset of the clients short and long terms is without rival."

— **Michael Ortiz**, Senior Asset Manager, Portfolio Management, West Region, Digital Realty Trust, was with another company when working with Geoff at Arizona Commerce Authority

"Geoff is an absolute professional in everything he does. His commitment to excelling beyond expectations and delivering more than expected is one of his core strengths. Geoff's commitment to quality, his work ethic, his focus, and his ability to find solutions to challenging problems through collaboration make him a tremendous asset. He is a professional counsel and a good friend."

### — **Jeff Anger**, worked directly with Geoff at ID Watchdog / Lifelock

"Geoff is an excellent consultative sales professional with proficient oral and written skills. He knows how to source and secure effective business deals and understands the big picture. He works productively with all levels of the organization and can be counted on to deliver positive results. His great personality and highly polished skills would be an asset to any organization."

### — **Dennis Taibl**, managed Geoff at ID Watchdog / Lifelock

"I have known Geoff for almost 10 years and his business acumen and professional demeanor are first class. Geoff has an amazing ability to establish solid relationships and work with individuals from all walks of life. His ability to open doors and build relationships with individuals, organizations, and companies is a true testament to not only his knowledge of any market sector, but his overall character as an individual. It was a gret pleasure working with Geoff during our time at Pulte and I am sure if you get the opportunity to work with him in the future, you will find that my remarks hold true."

— Chris Petroff, worked directly with Geoff at TW Lewis / Pulte / Del Webb

Contact Geoff on LinkedIn